Guide to the Consumer Reports. Lynn Jordan papers, 1970-1983 and undated RL.11820
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Lynn Jordan papers
1970-1983 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11820
1.2 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Lynn Jordan was a consumer rights advocate, President of the Virginia Citizens Consumer Council and a member of the Board of Directors of Consumers Union in the 1970s. The Lynn Jordan papers include clippings, correspondence, government documents, pamphlets, reports, testimonies and other printed materials that document Jordan's work in consumer education and protection as a representative of the Virginia Citizens Consumer Council and other organizations. Topics addressed include beef quality and grading, consumer credit, food prices, gender discrimination, patient rights, prescription drug prices, supermarkets, as well as the consumer effects of wage and price freezes resulting from the Economic Stabilization Act of 1973. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Subject Files
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Lynn Jordan was a consumer rights advocate, President of the Virginia Citizens Consumer Council and a member of the Board of Directors of Consumers Union in the 1970s.
Lynn Jordan (born 1943) served as president of the Virginia Citizens Consumer Council, based in Springfield, Va., during the 1970s. She was active in advocating for consumer rights both locally in Fairfax County and at the national level. Jordan also served as the head of the Fairfax County Consumer Commission and on the Board of Directors of Consumers Union. She was the founder of the Council of Consumer Organizations and co-founder of the National Consumer Congress.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Lynn Jordan papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Alvin A. Achenbaum papers
Consumer Reports. Advocacy records
Consumer Reports Archives records
Consumer Reports. Board of Directors records
Giant Food Stores advertising collection
J. Walter Thompson Company. Marketing vertical files
McGraw-Hill Marketing Information Center vertical files
Collection Overview
The Lynn Jordan papers include clippings, correspondence, government documents, pamphlets, reports, testimonies and other printed materials that document Jordan's work in consumer education and protection as a representative of the Virginia Citizens Consumer Council and other organizations. Topics addressed include beef quality and grading, consumer credit, food prices, gender discrimination, patient rights, prescription drug prices, supermarkets, as well as the consumer effects of wage and price freezes resulting from the Economic Stabilization Act of 1973.
Consumer advocacy; Consumer education; consumer protection; Credit; Sex discrimination against women; Price regulation; Wage-price policy; Prescriptions; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Jordan, Lynn
- General Files, 1972-1979; 1
  - Colston Warne speech--Consumer Innovators of Yesteryear, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Virginia Citizens' Consumer Council--Voice of the Virginia Consumer newsletter and other materials, 1972-1979; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Virginia Knauer speeches, 1973 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Virginia Knauer served as Special Assistant to the President for Consumer Affairs
- Subject Files: Issues and History, 1970-1983 and undated; 2
  - A&P supermarket, 1973-1975 (Box 1)
  - Advertising, 1971-1977 (Box 1)
  - Airlines, 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Automobile repair, 1973-1976 (Box 1)
  - Battle Hymn of the Consumer, undated (Box 1)
  - Beef boycott, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Bottle bill (S. 978/HR 122), 1972-1974 (Box 1)
  - Consumer/Patient rights, 1972-1978; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Consumer Product Safety Commission--Nomination of S. John Byington, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Consumerism, 1973-1976 (Box 1)
  - Consumers/Customer relations in business, 1980-1982 (Box 2)
  - Consumers Union--State of the Consumer message, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Consumers Union--"The Letter" to Colston Warne on grant funding, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Credit, 1970-1977; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Drug Fair, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Drugs--Prescription prices, 1973-1975 (Box 2)
  - Economic Stabilization Act, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Economics--Mary Ryan/Tibor Scitovsky, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Fairfax Consumer Protection Commission, 1973-1981 (Box 2)
  - Fairfax County Commission on the Status of Women, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Food Editors Conference, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Gasoline--Pricing suit, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Ground beef, 1971-1975; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Healthcare, 1976 (Box 2)
  - J.C. Penney--Who Speaks for the Consumer?, undated (Box 3)
  - Jerry Voorhis--Speech to American Council on Consumer Interests, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Lawn products, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Mail order merchandise, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Occupational licensing, 1974-1978 (Box 3)
  - Open burning, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Opticians/Optometry, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Organizing for Consumer Protection, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Outdoor Power Equipment Institute, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Price freeze, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Smoking, 1971-1983; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Steel prices, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Supermarkets, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Supermarkets--Price wars, 1981 (Box 3)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture--Food prices and productivity, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Virginia Canners Association, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Virginia Weights and Measures Association, 1973 (Box 3)